mastercam.com 2014-06-20

# Mastercam : Legal

CNC Software, Inc. (CNC), would like to thank you for visiting our website. We know many visitors have questions regarding the privacy of their interactions with CNC. We hope this privacy policy statement will answer any questions you may have, but if it does not, please feel free to contact us at the email address or postal address shown below.

Please note that most Mastercam® products are sophisticated computer-aided manufacturing software products aimed at small and large shops , mechanical engineers and other manufacturing and design professionals. Mastercam products generally have a suggested retail price of thousands of USDollars per license and CNC does not consider Mastercam products to be consumer products. 

The **Contents** of this statement are organized as follows:

**A.Online Privacy/ Marketing Contacts and Privacy/ License Activation and/or License Registration and Privacy**

  * Information Collected about Online Visitors
  * Entities Collecting Information
  * Information Collected via Marketing Activities
  * Information Collected via License Activation and/or License Registration
  * The Use of Personal Information Collected 
  * Updating Personal Information and "Opting Out"
  * Changes to This Policy

**B.Mastercam Discussion Forum**

**  
C.Third Party Sites**

**  
D.Technical Support, Special Cases, and Privacy**

  * Information Collected in Connection with Technical Support and the Use of That Information 
  * Customer Feedback Program

**A. Online Privacy/ Marketing Contacts and Privacy/ License Activation and/or License Registration and Privacy**

**  
Information Collected from Online Visitors**

In general, you can visit the Mastercam website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself, such as your name, phone number, or postal or email address. Our web server collects IP addresses to obtain certain aggregate information concerning the use of our website. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you’re surfing the web. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information. Therefore you can remain anonymous when you visit our website.

Our web servers also collect information such as number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed, etc., but this information is not traceable back to an individual user. CNC uses this information to analyze how people use our site and generate ideas on how the site might be improved.

Some of our web pages utilize "cookies" so that we can better serve you with tailored information when you return to our site. Cookies are identifiers that a web site can send to your browser to keep on your computer to facilitate your next visit to our site. It may do such things as store the fact that you have registered for a seminar so that the next time you visit the site we recognize that you are a registrant. You can, if you wish, set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it.

Occasionally you may be asked to give us more specific information about yourself, such as when you download software, register for a seminar or other event, respond to a survey, or enter a contest from our website. Supplying such information to us is optional, but you may be unable to complete certain transactions without giving such information.

**Entities collecting personal information**

The information provided at this site is collected by CNC Software, Inc., 671 Old Post Road, Tolland, Connecticut, 06084. Our telephone number is (860) 875-5006.  
This website contains links to websites owned and maintained by other companies. Such websites may also collect personal information and such collection of personal information will be subject to the privacy policies of the site and company at which it is collected.

**Information Collected via Marketing Activities**

CNC conducts many different marketing activities by which it may collect your personal information. For example, we collect individual contact information at trade shows, we run contests for which participants provide basic information on registration, we obtain addresses from publications that target the industries from which we hope to attract customers, we obtain attendee lists from trade shows that we participate in, and we obtain publicly available lists from sources that compile their information specific to the industries and related industries that we are in.

**Information Collected via License Activation and/or License Registration**

At the time customers license of a copy, or copies, of Mastercam® software through an authorized entity, CNC collects information such as Company name, shipping address, contact name, contact email address, telephone number, title, role, products designed, primary product in use and industry sector. CNC requests this information because it believes it is important to understand who its customers are and how to contact them with relevant product information. In some circumstances, CNC may be obligated to make this information available to third parties who license to CNC, technology that is included in the products being activated. If CNC receives an inquiry from a person at the licensee company as to which individual at the company has activated a given license, CNC will supply the contact name in response to enable the company to understand where its licenses are being used.

**The Use of Personal Information**

CNC may use the personal information you provide us for a variety of purposes, including registration, authentication, and marketing. We may use the information to inform you of special offers, contests, upgrades, and other Mastercam® software products and services that may be of interest to you. When you are a customer of Mastercam products or services, we may use your personal information to contact you for a wide array of customer relation/customer service purposes, such as to inquire whether you intend to renew maintenance agreements or other contracts with CNC or to request that you respond to a survey concerning our products and services or to address a question regarding an order.

Since Mastercam resellers are our primary sales channel and provide the first line of support to our customers, the information we receive about you commonly comes from them when Mastercam products are licensed. If you have contacted us first about a Mastercam Product or service, we share personal contact information with the reseller assigned to a particular region, customer, or prospect.

Some of the marketing information we provide you may also contain materials concerning the products and/or services of other third parties that enhance or augment Mastercam Products. Unless we inform you otherwise at the point at which we collect your information, we will not provide your personal contact information directly to a third party not otherwise described herein.

Mastercam products are not marketed to children under the age of 13 and CNC does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. CNC is committed to protecting the privacy of children and if CNC becomes aware that such information was collected, it will treat that information as sensitive. However, CNC does market to educational facilities and educators that may have students in this age group. CNC feels the Educational market is an important market for the future of the Manufacturing industry. 

If you do not wish to receive information about additional Mastercam products or services or those of its partners, please let us know (contact information below) and we will respect your wishes. 

CNC stores the personal data of web site visitors and customers indefinitely and may maintain and process such information directly or indirectly in one or more databases in the United States and elsewhere. We may hire other companies to provide services on our behalf that may involve the storage and use of your personal information, such as for delivering mailings or emails. Any such company or third party is required to maintain the confidentiality of that information and is prohibited from using that information for any purpose other than as authorized by us. If you provide personal information to CNC, you agree and consent to the storage and usage of this information anywhere that CNC and its affiliates maintain offices (around the world), for a variety of purposes, including those described above. 

CNC may also disclose such personal information if required by law or if CNC believes in good faith that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (for example, a warrant or subpoena or other court order) or protect the rights, property or personal safety of CNC, our customers or the public.

**Updating Personal Information and "Opting Out"**

CNC wants to ensure that the information it collects is accurate. You may notify us of any change to your address, phone number, email address or other information by sending us an email message at [privacy@Mastercam.com](mailto:privacy@Mastercam.com) or by notifying us in writing at:

CNC Software, Inc.  
671 Old Post Road  
Tolland, Connecticut 06084

If at any time you wish to "opt out" of receiving information from CNC, please notify us by sending us an email or written message to the addresses shown above or by emailing us at [remove@Mastercam.com](mailto:remove@Mastercam.com) . Please note that due to lead times on certain mailings and other contacts, you may continue to receive contacts for a period following your "opt out" notification.

**Changes to this Policy**

CNC may change this policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted to this site, so we encourage you to review our privacy policy from time to time.

**B. Mastercam Discussion Forum**

CNC participates in various Community activities with its users, including Discussion Forums on www.emastercam.com. CNC does not manage a discussion forum directly. Participation in these activities is voluntary and it is very likely that personal information will be exposed to other members of the Community if you participate. Some users prefer to participate using pseudonyms, but email addresses are required. CNC takes no responsibility for maintaining the privacy of any personal information you make available to members of any Community identified in or other similar websites.

**C. Third Party Sites**

This website contains links to websites owned and maintained by other companies. Such websites may also collect personal information and such collection of personal information will be subject to the privacy policies of the site and company at which it is collected. CNC is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any non- CNC website. Please review the privacy policy of such other sites before providing them with your personal information.

**D. Technical Support, Special Cases and Privacy**

**Information Collected in Connection with Technical Support and the Use of That Information**

Generally, CNC technical support group can obtain customer contact information via the serial number and registration data it maintains in its customer database. CNC may use this contact information to respond to support inquiries and/or to request additional information from the customer. 

Occasionally CNC must obtain files and/or model information to assist it in diagnosing their technical support issues. CNC may share model and file information provided by a customer with a licensor of technology that is included in a Mastercam product if CNC considers that appropriate to assist it in diagnosing or resolving a customer problem. All of such licensors are also contractually obligated to protect the confidentiality of customer models and files.

If files are required to diagnose a problem, or to provide training or support on a specific application, and are considered highly confidential, CNC can enter into a non-disclosure agreement with you or your company to ensure the confidential nature of your work.

Some third party software that interoperates with the Mastercam software, such as Microsoft’s Windows Vista® operating system software, may request data from your system in order to assist it in diagnosing issues. You will be informed of the need for this information and may choose whether to provide it to the third party. The third party will be responsible for any privacy issues related to the information you provide it.

CNC also maintains many of the customer files in a database it uses to conduct regression tests and other tests of later releases of the Mastercam software.

**Customer Feedback Program**

The Mastercam products include an optional feedback tool that, if turned on, sends basic system and usage information to CNC via the Internet. The feedback tool is turned off by default and can only be turned on by the user. It may be turned off and on repeatedly at the option of the user through the Help menu, and we may choose to ask again at a future date. This data is used only for quality and product improvement purposes and helps give CNC an idea of the relative value of various functionalities within its products along with hardware and software trends in the user community. The data does not include any user model data or any information that could be used to re-create models, and is reviewed by CNC in the aggregate. All information collected in this program is confidential. 

We hope this policy statement helps you understand CNC practices with respect to your personal and business information. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us as indicated above under the heading **Updating Personal Information and "Opting Out."**
